Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer: The Movie is a animation, family,
music film directed by William R. Kowalchuk Jr..
Young Rudolph suffers a childhood accident that sees his nose turn from the
publicly accepted norm of black to a glowing red colour.
His parents worry about him getting teased, and indeed he does in the end.
When he is beaten in the reindeer games by his rival for a doe he fancies,
Rudolph runs away and moves into a cave with Slyly the Fox.
However can he overcome his fear and reach his true potential?
Young Rudolph (voice), played by Eric Pospisil.
Older Rudolph / Twinkle the Spirte (voice), played by Kathleen Barr.
Santa Claus (voice), played by John Goodman.
Stormella (voice), played by Whoopi Goldberg.
Mrs. Claus / Mitzi / Mrs. Prancer / School Teacher
(voice), played by Debbie Reynolds.
Leonard (voice), played by Bob Newhart.
Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer is a fictional reindeer created by Robert L.
Rudolph is usually depicted as the ninth and youngest of Santa Claus's reindeer, using his
luminous red nose to lead the reindeer team and guide Santa's sleigh on Christmas Eve.
Though he initially receives ridicule for his nose as a fawn, the brightness of his nose is
so powerful that it illuminates the team's path through harsh winter weather.
Lankford, Jr., described Rudolph's story as "the fantasy story made to order for American children: each child
has the need to express and receive approval for their individuality and special qualities.
Rudolph's story embodies the American Dream for the child, writ large because of the cultural significance of
Christmas."
Rudolph first appeared in a 1939 booklet written by May and published by Montgomery Ward, the department store.
The story is owned by The Rudolph Company, LP and has been adapted into numerous forms including the song by Johnny Marks, the television special Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer, Rudolph's Shiny New Year, and Rudolph and
Frosty's Christmas in July from Rankin/Bass Productions, as well as Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer: The Movie and Rudolph the Red-Nosed Reindeer and the Island of Misfit Toys from GoodTimes Entertainment.
Character Arts, LLC manages the licensing for the
Rudolph Company, LP and DreamWorks Classics.
In many countries, Rudolph has become a figure of Christmas folklore.
2014 marked the 75th anniversary of the character and the 50th
anniversary of the Rankin/Bass television special.
A series of postage stamps featuring Rudolph was issued by the
United States Postal Service on November 6, 2014.
The film explores themes of snow, christmas spirit, christmas.